Vitor Miranda

Web Developer

Personal Info

Address

323 Colborne Street, London-ON, N6B3N8

Phone

+1 (647) 937-9470

E-mail

vcmiranda@outlook.com

Github

https://github.com/vcmiranda

LinkedIn

https://ca.linkedin.com/in/vcmiranda

Skills

Front end development - HTML, CSS (Bootstrap), Javascript, JQuery

Front end framework - Vue.js (Vuex, Vue-router, Vuetify)

Design Tools - Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator

Back end development - Node.js, Express.js, Knex.js

Database - MySQL, MSSQL, Oracle

Server - Linux, Windows

Web Hosting Solutions - Google Cloud, Microsoft Azure

Microsoft Project Management - MS Project, MS Project Online, MS Project Server

Microsoft Sharepoint

Microsoft BI Solution - SSRS, SSAS, Power BI Full stack web developer, specializing in front end development (proficient in Vue.JS, and learning React). Solid project management background, being responsible or having participated of the deployment of solutions in a variety of domains. Provided in-company training to more than 1000 people in project management software. Responsible for the growth and mentoring of other team members (developing intern technical and management skills).

Experience

2017-05 -

Full Stack Web Developer

present

Sport-Travel - London, ON

- Frontend Development HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Vue.js
- Backend Development Node.js, Express.js
- Project deployment using Google Cloud Compute Engine with LAMP stack, or Google
 App Engine, and continuous integration using Travis
- Unit testing using Mocha and Chai
- CRUD using Knex,js, and MySQL / Postgres
- Handle authentication using Firebase
- Control source code and administer project issues using Git and Github
- Conduct project using Trello Agile methodology
- Work with clients to establish system requirements and design

2017-01 -

Peer Tutor

2018-01

Fanshawe College - London, ON

• Supported academic development of other students by assisting in the understanding of concepts in Programming (Javascript, PHP), Network, Database (MSSQL, Oracle), and Web Design (Photoshop, HTML, CSS), improving their grades in 25% average.

2012-08 -

Project Management Consultant/Instructor

2016-03

Prosperi Tecnology - Vitoria, BR

- Conducted software projects, handling all the aspects of management, development, and deployment using Microsoft PPM Solution (Sharepoint, Project Server/Project Online, Project, and BI Solutions SSRS, SSAS, Power BI), generating around \$160,000 in revenue.
- Administered project risks, issue and constraints, reducing change requests in 33% of the projects
- Provided training for over a 1000 people in project management software
- Developed custom training material according to the client's needs

2014-03 -

College Professor

2016-02

UCL – Centro Leste College - Serra, BR

- Taught planning using project management software to more than 200 students
- Provided relevant assignments for students that demonstrate learning outcomes in a real-life setting
- Facilitated access of project management tools and training materials

2015-01 -

2016-01

Coordinator

Microsoft Innovation Center - Vitoria, BR

- Provided open training in IT to the community, focused on the development of more than 100 students in Microsoft technology (Infrastructure and software development)
- Managed team of 4 students/developers that developed Windows apps, according to Microsoft requirements
- Provided free lectures related to Microsoft technology and presented by Microsoft evangelists to the community

Development Tools - REST, Gulp, JSON, Webpack

Software Version Control - Git, Github

2011-04 - Planning and PMO Analyst

Concremat Engineering and Technology Inc - Vitoria, BR

- Improved, with PMO team, a project management methodology based on market best practices, reducing project time in 15%, and budget in 12%
- Directed team responsible for building processes workflow of an engineering department
- Developed a process to improve quality of schedules that has been built by planners, reducing rework in 32%
- Provided training in project management to a team of more 15 engineers
- Followed and managed risks in more than 20 projects at the same time
- Executed supplier evaluation process, improving deliverable quality in 24%

Education

2012-08

2016-09 -	Fanshawe College - London, ON
2018-04	Internet Application and Web Development
2007-03 -	UVV – Vila Velha University - Vitoria, Brazil
2008-12	MBA in Project Management
2001-08 -	UVV – Vila Velha University - Vitoria, Brazil
2006-12	Bachelor in Business Administration

Certificates

2013	MS Managing Project with Microsoft Project 2013
2013	MS Managing Project and Portfolios with Project Server 2013
2013	MCSE Core Solutions of Microsoft Sharepoint Server 2013
2012	MCTS Microsoft Project 2010, Managing Projects